the balance or exploit that recently happened, right? This incident, just like others that have
come before it, right? Reveal this really interesting tension. I think it's this idea that like
decentralization is not binary. Because ultimately after a hack or an exploit like I and I know
institutions and users don't want to have to wait around and be like, well, is the project going to
do anything to work for me? Is the community going to do anything to work for me? Is the government
going to say that this is a crime even though it's unsure if this is a crime? For all those betting
on polymarket as to crypto market structure passage? This is not investment advice, but I am,
I agree with me. I am very bearish that this is going to happen soon. Despite the president making
this a mandate like get this done. Hi all. Welcome to decks in the city where the wallets are cold
and the tapes are hot. There are a lot of boss women in crypto and we want to make sure you hear
from some of them. We're going to get to intros in a second, but we first want to frame why we're
doing this. There are a lot of crypto podcasts out there and you could be listening to any of those,
so why should you be listening to us? Well, between the three of us, we've worked in senior roles in
DeFi, C5, crypto banking, venture capital, infrastructure and more. We have insights on
trade buying crypto. We're on the front lines of crypto policy and we're pros at regulatory
engagement. We are also very good at breaking down the more complicated concepts into English.
Before we dive in, this is our very first edition. Very exciting and we're thrilled to bring decks
in the city to you as part of Unchained on air. The new slate of shows expanding the incredible
Unchained network. Before we get going, remember, very important. We're lawyers, but we're not your
lawyers. So nothing you hear on decks in the city is legal or financial advice and it doesn't
create an attorney client relationship. For the fine print, as always check unchainedcrypto.com.
So let's dive in. First, we have Jesse, Web3 prosecutor, turned Web3 protector at Ribbit Capital.
Hi, everyone. I am so glad we are finally doing this. I want to do a quick shout out to Laura and
the entire Unchained team. As you can probably tell, the technical infrastructure that goes into
this is very, very complex and they have been working on it for a long time and we just get
to join for the ride. So thank you guys so much. So I'm excited to do this pod because the three
of us spend so much time talking about this space and really debating off mic and sometimes over drinks,
which we'll maybe do sometimes on this pod as well. And now I can force the two of y'all to
hang out with me every week. So KK said I'm Jesse Brooks. Hello. I've spent about a decade in crypto.
It started in the national security world at the Department of Justice where I was taking on North
Korea terrorist networks that were engaging with crypto and hackers like the Bitfinex hackers.
And everyone else that was trying to make the safe space less safe for all of us,
especially at the beginning when it was building. Now I'm at Ribbit Capital,
which is an investment firm committed to backing rebels that are reinventing finance
across crypto, AI, and FinTech. Awesome, Jesse. And everyone needs to listen because hopefully,
one day you'll get to hear the famous Jesse Brooks ring, which is my personal favorite
in terms of engagement. Let's next move on to V from the SEC to Web3 V. Hi, everyone.
I'm V Lee, the general counsel at Veda, where we're building infrastructure
DeFi scale safely. Something we'll be talking about today. So I've been in crypto for over four years,
first at a digital identity protocol, then at a crypto VC, and most recently was the GC of the
only federally regulated crypto bank, which is actually still the only federally regulated crypto
company in the US period, which I think tells you a lot about how we still have to go on the
policy front. One of the things that we'll be talking about before crypto, I was your classic
trad fi lawyer, practice securities, law to big law firm spent almost six years at the SEC.
So suits, memos, windowless office, whole thing. But the SEC is also where I first fell down the
crypto rabbit hole working on crypto investigations. So I have government for that. But I'm so excited
to be doing this with two of my favorite people in crypto, Jesse and KK. So if you've ever wondered
what it would be like to be a fly on the wall and three female crypto GCs get together,
you'll get a taste of some of that on this show, not everything just. So we all have drinks,
we should choose to that very often. This is camomile tea, but I like it. Fantastic
be. And very important disclaimer with the V was not with SEC enforcement during the Gary
Gensler administration. So I needed to, you know, provide that disclaimer. And I'm your host,
Katherine or KK or KKB, any of the above. And I'm fluent in trad fi and conversant in deep tech
over at stark wear. So I was a white shoe big law partner doing basically all trad fi investigations
defending big entities asset managers in us government investigations. And then I too fell
down the crypto rabbit hole, loved it, saw the inherent inefficiencies in trad fi market structure
and understand how crypto can solve those. So I completely went off the defend and went to be
GC of a DeFi protocol. Then I moved to be chief legal officer of a centralized exchange, both
spot and derivatives and derivatives clearinghouse. So lots to say about the CFTC these days.
And I will just say day to day, we're going to tackle a lot of the crypto happenings,
but with some new takes, we're going to dive a little bit deeper and get into perspectives
that you do not hear on crypto Twitter, we're also going to correct crypto Twitter.
And we're going to have fun while we're doing it, because we're also real friends, not just
crypto friends. So that's an important distinction. So let's get into the meat of today. So I have
to say in the theme of self promotion here, Jesse and I released an academic paper a couple weeks
ago on programmable risk management. We were very excited about this. But it did create a little
bit of spice amongst certain nerds in the population. And I think our take on it is that a lot of
people didn't read the 20 plus paper, which I completely understand. But the thesis that we
set forth in this paper was basically there are theoretically ways to improve upon DeFi. We love
DeFi. I mean, my heart is with DeFi was my first GC role. Now, one of the things that we were saying
in the paper is we outlined a whole laundry list of tech based solutions that theoretically would
not disrupt the UX that would not re intermediate DeFi. And we said these should be optional solutions
for discussion within DeFi and maybe certain protocols in, you know, conversing with their
community in achieving their goals might want to consider these. And many already exist and are
being considered to exactly many of them are already being used today. Exactly. I mean, blockchain
analytics is one extreme side of things because most DeFi protocols are using blockchain analytics
as the bare minimum. But there were a multitude of other solutions. To be very clear, we are not
and we're not arguing that DeFi should be regulated or re intermediated in any way.
So I want to kick us off here because I know the three of us have a lot of thoughts about
the safety of DeFi, what solutions exist. Why don't we go right into it? You know,
V, let's get us started. Kick us off. What are your thoughts on all things programmable risk
compliance, programmable risk management. I read it before it was published. I read a manuscript
of it. So it was so honored to be able to do that. So if you guys haven't read this paper,
it's groundbreaking. And I really think you should. We'll link it in the show notes.
I also wrote a paper last week or an article for law 360. For those of you who don't know,
law 360 is a legal publication that at least was my daily reading when I was a law firm
associate in clerking and in government. But in the paper, I talk specifically about chain capital
markets and how issuers and users aren't going to participate unless they feel like they can
trust these markets to be fair and gritty. And I look at some of the solutions that, you know,
like they can just see just said, some of the solutions that the industry is already, you know,
developing and using to build safeguards directly into things like tokens and smart contracts
with respect to order execution quality, maybe the mitigation tools, that sort of thing.
So along the same lines as KK and Jesse's paper of, you know, instead of regulatory mandates,
what are some ways that the industry can leverage the technology itself to keep users safe and
combat things like illicit finance? So I think, like you guys said, I think the feedback on both
of these pieces has been really interesting. First, I'll say, and I think you guys agree with this,
right? We welcome and encourage debate and disagreement. Like, these are really hard issues that we're
all trying to figure out together. And I think all of us are committed to crypto's core values of
decentralization and inclusion and transparency and censorship resistance, right? So, you know,
but I do think the debates raised some really like hard questions about DeFi that are worth
discussing in a nuanced way, which social media doesn't always lend itself to. So all kick things
off for us, right? So for me, I think a lot of the DeFi debate comes down to two fundamental
questions, right? One is what responsibility do we have to keep users safe? And relatedly,
what responsibility do we have to offer users recourse when things go wrong? So I think it's really
easy to say, yes, we're in favor of, you know, pure DeFi or true DeFi. But then how do you answer
those questions? And how do we see DeFi protocols actually answering those questions in real life,
right? So I think, you know, there are two recent events that me really illustrated
this tension. First was the Balancer exploit that recently happened, right? So Balancer is a DeFi
exchange. It recently suffered an exploit where the attacker drained $28 million from liquidity
pools, manipulating the pricing function, and the pool balances to basically trick the protocol
into miscalculating the value of the tokens. And then they repeatedly performed swaps to
deflate the price, and then either minted or bought the undervalued tokens,
immediately redeemed them in a way that allowed them to drain the pools. So how did Balancer
respond to this? I think most of their pools do not have an admin key or like a kill switch.
But there were some pools that were able to be paused, and they did that, they paused them.
They alerted users, and then they worked with White House to recover the funds. And what was
also really interesting about this incident is that the different chains that were affected
responded in really different ways, right? So Ethereum largely stuck to the code as law ethos,
so they didn't do any rollbacks, no forks, the losses remained on chain. But there were a bunch
of smaller side chains and L2s that it intervened, and validators or sequencers temporarily halted
block production, or they coordinated soft forks to freeze the hacker's distance, and others actually
did perform a hard work. Reverse or isolate the impact of the attack, right? So for me,
this incident, just like others that have come before it, right, revealed this really interesting
tension. I think it's this idea that like decentralization is not binary, meaning even chains that
claim to be or aspire to be immutable or permissionless, sometimes do feel the need to intervene
when users are or lose funds, right? So I think this really puts the idea of pure DeFi through
the test, right? So I think we need to ask ourselves, like, when a network can be forked to recover
used funds, does that create some sort of like de facto fiduciary duty or something like that,
among validators of that? 100, 100%. And before we move to Jesse, I just want to clarify one thing,
a white hat hacker, a lot of people I realized didn't understand what that was. If they're not
in crypto, a white hat hacker is kind of a good guy. And what you often see with exploits in crypto,
or not often, but occasionally is there's a hacker who facilitates an exploit, and whatever entity
is in charge or a community member will then go to them and say, we'll pay you if you turn into a
white hat, like if you give the money back. So this was not the case here, but white hats help the
ecosystem. But Jesse, please jump it. Yeah, let me just give you a little insider knowledge on
white hat hackers as well. These predated crypto for many people who have been in the cybersecurity
national security world for quite some time. And actually, the government relies on them
for a lot of sort of early cybersecurity, national security issues. So it's just sort of something
to think about how it's also been incorporated in crypto in a variety of ways. But I actually
think that these two questions sort of level setting are very, very thoughtful. And I'll just add a
third one, which is who should give the recourse? Should it be the protocol? Should be the community?
Should it be the government, the courts, which we're going to talk about some of the stuff that's
happening there, particularly with the MIT brothers case that we'll cover in a little bit.
But also, I just want to put forward like what kind of world do we want to live in where users
have to think about how do I get recourse for something bad happening, instead of having the
choice from the start of being much, much more comfortable of where they put their finances
before something bad happens. And I think that sort of the debate here is how much can we embed
in the native aspect of crypto and DeFi and all the projects that are built in it to make users less
worried about any sort of hack and who they'll need to go to for recourse later on. Because to me,
like decentralization is not about having no rules or standards, but it's rather about a bottom up
choice of how to embed rules and standards if you want or not. And a choice by the users, a choice
by the projects, a choice by the protocols, the choice to opt into more security and safety when
they want it or more risk and maybe more upside if they don't want it. Because isn't that like
really what we're building here in my mind? Like the crypto ecosystem is about giving people in my
mind at least more power over their finances, whether it be self custody, whether it be how
they want to engage with DeFi. And it should also be the opportunity to engage in a more risk forward
or risk conservative manner. Because ultimately after a hack or an exploit like I and I know
institutions and users don't want to have to wait around and be like, well, is the project going
to do anything to work for me? Is the community going to do anything to work for me? Is the government
going to say that this is a crime even though it's unsure if this is a crime? Instead, why don't we
allow users to say, okay, here are all the options out there and let's go from there. And on that
point, like, isn't it better that we work from the ground up than have sort of this regulatory
oversight coming afterwards or trying to figure out how to fit things within crimes in order to
give recourses to users? Power to the people, Jesse, I love it. And it's no, but it's true. Like,
you make a great point in that I think the fear in with respect to some of the radical pure DeFi
advocacy that we've seen lately is that there's a fear that if we even open up the discussion
as to so-called protections to put in place, that regulators or legislators are going to seize on
that as a way of regulating DeFi or mandating such checks. And I completely understand and
acknowledge that fear because there should be a scenario where pure DeFi exists without checks,
eyes wide open, you know, there's a beauty of transparency with DeFi that we all understand
and acknowledge. Like, I would always explain that to people that didn't understand crypto,
vis-a-vis maple, my first DeFi project, that it's midnight, the payment for the loan is due at
midnight, 1201, everyone can see it's not paid, which is, you know, beautiful thing about on-chain
activity, you know, DeFi lending doesn't exist in tradFi, right? But I think your point is really
important. Like, shouldn't we also empower builders that maybe they want to go more conservative,
maybe they want to serve a population, regulated entities, institutional participants, one-day
pension funds, and they want to, you know, ensure that they're taking a more conservative route without
being penalized in the DeFi community by not being pure DeFi? Because I don't view a lot of this as
reintermediating DeFi. A lot of it can be inserted without disrupting the peer-to-peer UX.
Can I ask you guys as like DeFi project GCs, don't you think about this kind of thing on day-to-day?
Like, what comes up when you sort of make the considerations of how you were going to build?
Is it all or nothing? Like, how do you guys think about pure DeFi and building in the space?
Oh my gosh, so many things I want to follow up on. So, Jesse, I wanted to follow up on one
point that you made that I think is really important, which is like, one of the benefits of DeFi and
these DeFi protocols is that you know ahead of time what's going to happen, right? Like,
everyone can see the code, everyone knows how the protocol is going to behave. But when these hacks
and these exploits and attacks happen, the response is always so at home. Like, you said, right? Like,
no one knows what is going to happen. Like, is anyone going to intervene to like help return
the funds? Like, what is going to happen? No one knows. So, I think for that reason alone,
we should probably, you know, at least be able to talk about it. Should there be some standards in
place? Like, are there tools that people can use? Like, what are best practices here?
And that is something that is missing, I think, right now. And obviously, these events are going
to keep happening, right? I think it's only fair to users to be able to know ahead of what they're
getting themselves into. And that's the very part to people, though, is those standards. You know,
I think that's the scary part because they don't want to, we don't want to mandate standards that
would basically harm DeFi holistically. However, it's really interesting. I think everyone occasionally
forgets that, you know, what DeFi protocol exists without a smart contract audit. Like,
that's a self-imposed industry standard for safety, right? Because it's common sense. You
want your smart, you know, you don't want to engage with a protocol that hasn't had,
you know, an audited smart contract. So, I would love to see the industry growing in a way where,
and again, I said this before, but blockchain analytics, a lot of general councils of Devco's,
etc. We always think through risk. Like, I like to sleep at night, you know, we don't want to
facilitate wrongdoing in any form, even inadvertently or, you know, not knowingly, of course. Now,
there's a criminal threshold, you need to have intent to be convicted of a crime. However,
that gets very sticky with things like civil liability for sanctions, which we'll get into
at another time because it's kind of complicated. But I think that's the role of the GC, and especially
in crypto. It's not to eliminate risk. Like, absolutely not. It's to educate the company about
the risk. It's the issue spot. So then they're armed with that information and can make informed
decisions. You know, to your question about, like, are we thinking about it, like,
perch of the GC working at a DeFi company or a DeFi protocol? I guarantee you, every single DeFi
project out there is constantly like on a daily basis to balance decentralization and the principles
of decentralization against user safety, like keeping their user safe. This is something we
think about instantly. And it's a struggle. I mean, it's something that I have to deal with
with respect to new features that the team wants to act or a new design mechanism. Every DeFi
project out there thinking about this. So I think the other reason I hope we can sort of
move beyond the pure DeFi or the all-or-nothing debate is that I just don't think that that
is the reality of what most DeFi projects and companies are dealing with. As DeFi goes
more mainstream, I think the other dynamic we're starting to see, and we certainly think about it
in these terms too, the other dynamic you're going to start seeing is, you know, if you're able to
create protocols or kits where users feel safe, that is going to be like a competitive business
advantage for you. So that's the other thing, right? I think this isn't just like it's not a
philosophical or academic debate anymore. Like DeFi is gaining adoption. It is going mainstream.
Now we have to think about what are the market opportunities, but that's the other way we think.
That's absolutely right. And I think that's something a lot of us like we've discussed before.
If the trad and crypto markets are converging pure DeFi without even discussion of this,
I mean, I am skeptical that it will ever scale. I'm also sympathetic, however, because there's also
the balance between kind of paternalistic measures. So this is not an easy conversation by any
stretch. So I want to move to Jesse to talk about the MIT Rose case. This is a fascinating case
because I feel like it got no attention from anyone. And, you know, it's so random to me what gets
a lot of attention and discussion and what does it. This was an important one. So Jesse,
please educate everyone. I think people must have just been exhausted of like tracking day-to-day
crypto trials that they needed to break. But I am similarly surprised that this didn't get a lot
of attention because it presents a really interesting aspect of the law that hasn't fully been touched
on point in prior criminal cases. But, you know, just back to level setting, like to me,
the big question of this pod today is like, who's going to enforce the rules when code alone isn't
enough? And this is a case when the courts tried to enforce it. And it didn't really go so great.
And we maybe have less clarity than we did before. But just to give like a two-sentence overview on
what this case was about, essentially, these very technically savvy brothers exploited a
vulnerability in Ethereum's MEV Boost relay code. And in so exploiting this, they extracted
$25 million from bots that were engaged in sandwich attacks. And the argument that they made is that
they simply found a bug in code and they targeted bots that were already manipulating the markets,
like not the most sympathetic victims, right? They say they didn't lie to anybody, so there's no fraud.
They didn't directly interact with the victims, no contractual relationship. And they didn't
violate any of the rules or standards, the two words we've been using a lot today, of the decentralized
Ethereum network. And I slowly say decentralized Ethereum network, because obviously it might work
differently on other networks and might have been charged differently. But the government said,
like, "Pishposh, no, we disagree. This is wire fraud and conspiracy and money laundering,
but focusing on the wire fraud, because that was the real issue at trial." And the question was,
what was the fraud? So the government argued that it was the bait transactions and the false
signatures. And the technical aspects of them were really interesting in the trial and the
specific details of this are really important. But I think what's even more interesting is that
after a few weeks of a very technical trial, and for anyone here that has been in trial or
had any sort of component of a trial, you know how hard it is to explain these complicated concepts
to people off the street. But after days of deliberation, the jury could not come to an agreement. So
they say that the jury was hung. Let me just take a quick sidebar to explain what that means. So
essentially in a criminal trial, the jury has to unanimously decide the defendant is guilty of this
charge or unanimously decide they are not guilty. Those are really the options and it happens for
each charge. And if they can't come to an agreement, they come and tell the judge, "Hey, we can't come
to an agreement." Usually the judge says, "Go back and keep arguing." The prosecutor says, "Go back
and keep arguing." The defense usually says they're not going to come to an agreement. And if it gets
to a point where it's pretty clear they won't, which happened in this case after some very emotional
jury notes, which are somewhat odd in these circumstances, the judge decided that they weren't ever going
to agree. And so they declare a mistrial. What happens with a mistrial is that the prosecution
gets to decide whether it wants to bring the case again. What happens behind the scenes is that the
prosecution decides do we want to drop the case? Do we want to offer a plea or do we just want to go
to trial again? So we don't know what's going to happen and they have a few weeks to come back and
decide. But I think the bigger question that sort of fits in here is we have an exploit. Maybe it
hurt not so sympathetic victims this time. But thinking about the bigger picture for users that
might have been hurt in some sort of vulnerability attack, why are we leaving it to 12 random people
off the street to decide after a few weeks of trying to learn about these technical issues
that this is or isn't a crime? Like is that the best way for us to move forward in this space?
And it rhymes a lot with what happened in the Mango markets case where a guy named Abi Eisenberg
didn't exploit a vulnerability or bug, but he rather manipulated the platform's own oracle
according to the government's allegation. And then a jury found him guilty and then an appellate judge
overturned the convictions. So in both of them, the court system tried, but I don't want to say
failed, but sort of seemingly failed to come to a decision that gives the space any clarity.
And this is why it comes back to my argument before of like, we should give choice in protocols
for users and institutions to build what they want, what kind of risk they want,
because in the world that we live in right now, you don't know where to go for recourse. So
that's sort of the framework we're living in right now.
And fun fact, I was once on a jury for a check fraud case, and it's highly unusual for a lawyer,
like, especially with what we've done historically. No, you never get picked because there's this
process called raw deer where they vet the jury members. And so there's peremptory challenges
where the lawyers can strike juries for cause like, oh, you're biased or so usually I would have
been struck through a peremptory challenge because I knew too much about criminal law because I was
a white collar defense attorney, but I somehow ended up on the jury. And afterward, the judge was
like, the defense blew through all their peremptory challenges. So he was stuck with you. And of course,
I do want to tell you, see, you have to keep lawyers on because there's so many lawyers. So
yeah, go by what kind of. And so statistically, you have no choice, but it was a fascinating
experience. So there we go. I'm just going to put that out there. So we're, we only have 12
minutes left. So I want to shift topics really quick to market structure, because it's important
to know like we were originally going to touch this, but hot news, the House Agriculture Committee
had advanced and then passed the clarity act back in July, this the crypto market structure bill
that we're all really excited about. And to explain to people, I'm constantly explaining to
people that aren't lawyers, why we're excited, there is a fear that all of the good work that
the regulators are doing right now in the United States vis-a-vis crypto, the SEC is a great example.
Their transparency, their engagement, et cetera, could be completely reversed if we have a different
administration with a different mandate in a few years. The only thing that will determinatively
prevent that is legislation. So that's why you see a lot of crypto people desperate for crypto
market structure legislation, even if it's not perfect. So a draft drop yesterday from the Senate
Agriculture Committee, because we need the House, we need the Senate, and then we need the President,
okay? So we got the House, the Senate's version is different, and this is why there's a big uphill
battle here, because there is basically efforts from the Senate Banking Committee, efforts from
the Senate Agriculture Committee, those need to be reconciled and cleared by both committees,
and then get passed in the Senate. So we have a lot of work to do, but this draft drop yesterday
from the Senate Ag Committee, and it was very different than the Banking Committee. And in keeping
with our theme today, like first, a lot of emphasis on the CFTC's mandate versus the SEC's,
a good protection of self custody, a direction for joint rulemaking with SEC and the CFTC.
AML anti-money laundering specifics are very vague, and the scope of CFTC exemption powers
are unclear. I call that out because it's really important that regulators have the power to grant
exemptions. But we've been talking about this a lot on this pod. There is a section on DeFi
with nothing in it. Like DeFi oversight is completely left completely open, which is a little scary
to people because we were all desperate and really hoping for explicit developer protections
in legislation. So, Jessie, it looks like you want to say something.
Yeah, before we jump it over to V, I want to play moderator for a second and just do one
extra level of explanation because, you know, unless you're on the hill all the time,
it's hard to understand all these different committees, what the heck's going on up there.
And so when Congress Committee jurisdiction drives everything, so CFTC is under ag and then
banking and financial banking takes over SEC and all financial regulation. So, the AG is
committee in the Senate. They have a bipartisan draft that came out yesterday. The Senate banking
committee, the Republicans have only really come out with an agreement. So, there's this
interesting strategic game playing right now where the Dems in the AG committee are trying to figure
out how do we put forward a bipartisan proposal that doesn't go against what all the Dems on the
banking committee are going saying. And that also competes with the fact that the AG committee
can't really regulate the kind of stuff that the banking committee should do, which sometimes
might be the ML stuff or the DeFi stuff. And you're going to see lots of brackets throughout
this new draft. So, it's Congress's version of like a sticky note saying, hey, we got to come back
to that because we haven't agreed yet. And so, that's sort of where like, who knows what DeFi,
who knows what the hell, who knows what the definition. So, I guess, like, I'll just turn it back to
you guys. You're like, what the heck should people get from this? And brackets are scary to people
because it's hard to make progress if you don't have the fundamentals agreed upon. So, I'm also
scared of the DeFi brackets. But the all the other thing I'll also explain to people is people are
often like, to me, especially non-US persons are like, why is the agriculture committee involved in
this? That's because you have to think of the definition of the OG commodity in the United States.
It's often things like cows and corn and wheat. So, like, that's why the AG committee is such a
big part of the crypto debate because crypto is a commodity. But the classic commodity,
like, as a Chicagoan, like, it was all of the farm animals. Like, there's a futures market for
a reason. Like, we'll get into that another time. So, V, jump in because I know you are also very
sophisticated on the policy. Yeah. So, I mean, I just wanted to touch on, like, you know,
I'm sure everyone's wondering, like, what is the process from here? Like, you know, you mentioned
that the two committees bills, like, eventually, hopefully, will be merged into some, like, senate
itch that will reconcile the CFTC jurisdiction. So, if both committees vote their versions out,
senate leadership has to agree to bring it to the floor, which is, like, always a hurdle, right?
Just given limited floor time and competing priorities, the fact that you need 60 votes to
overcome a filibuster, which means they're going to need some Democrats to support the Republicans.
And then if it passes, the senate bill would then be reconciled with the version that passed
of the House a while back, it seems like ages ago. But so, you know, negotiations or conference
committee, like, that would have to happen before being sent to the president. So, I mean, I think
in terms of timing, like, realistically, I don't think the process is going to wrap until 2026,
probably not until late 2026, maybe even early 2027. And then we also have, you know, the elections
next fall. So, that could also grow a wrench in things. Like, you know, I remain optimistic
that something will eventually pass. Like, both Republicans and Dems have an interest in this
passing. I think they're both sides are working really hard towards that. The momentum from the
industry is as strong as it's ever been. Stablecoin legislation, of course, passed earlier this year,
which I think, you know, only improves the market structures and since the passing,
even though it's a much more complicated undertaking. And then also the SEC, the CFTC
Treasury, I think they're also really pressuring Congress to act and are working closely with
them on the bills, right? So that really matters too. So yeah, my prediction is late 2026, early
2027. You know, that sounds so far off. But like, I will say, in the meantime, DeFi will keep
shipping. And I would also remind people that neither the SEC nor the CFTC is waiting around
for Congress, right? There's plenty they can do and are doing under their existing authority
as we speak. So don't worry, that will give us plenty to talk about on this podcast, even if
things don't move along in Congress. 100%. Like, I have been so heartened by the SEC. I mean,
the transparency, I mean, I'm obsessed with Hester Peirce in an in a purely academic way.
She's been making so much great progress as head of the crypto asset task force to transparency
that we're seeing and the engagement. It's what we all dreamed up for so long. The scary part is
a lot of this work can be undone. And Chair Atkins of the SEC has said that they are working to
try to avoid a scenario where the progress they're making can be undone. But the thing that will
really let me sleep at night is crypto market structure legislation. And of course, once the
legislation is passed, it's going to take years to actually create rules. And you know, it's that's
really a basis for what's to come. But for all those betting on polymarket as to crypto market
structure passage, this is not investment advice. But I am I agree with V, I am very bearish that
this is going to happen soon. Despite the president making this a mandate, like get this done,
there are just significant headwinds. And let's get out of our crypto bubble for a second. We all
need to remember that for many legislators, there's still a real education gap. They don't feel
comfortable with this industry. And this is just not a priority for them, especially with the,
you know, nonsense that we've been dealing with lately, like the other parts of dysfunction of our
government on day, what is it? Like 32 of the shutdown, by the way, or are you baby? Oh, my God,
I just all a blur to me, all a sad blur. But Jesse, do you want to wrap us up with any final thoughts?
I think I should just say it was so lovely to do this our first time together. And I am really
excited to keep debating with you guys throughout the next few months. Any final thoughts from UV?
No, this was so fun. Thanks guys. And cheers. So I think what's to come from us. So the beauty
of this is you'll hear our insights on the CFTC and the SEC and legislation. Oh, this is sounding
so sexy. I think you'll get to hear our thoughts on the legal policy, a strategy oriented environment
for crypto. You know, hopefully we'll be able to give everyone insight on all of the good, bad,
and ugly within this ecosystem. And we'll be able to correct a lot of things that you read on
crypto Twitter. I'm just going to reiterate that because that is the theme of my life. Like that's
wrong. That's wrong. That's wrong. Yeah, I added to be that's it for this episode, the very first
episode of Ducks in the City. If you like the show, make sure to follow us on your favorite podcast
app and on X slash Twitter will always be Twitter in my heart, even though I understand and recognize
that it has a new name for live streams, updates, and clips. Thank you so much for listening and
we will see you next week.